Right now, there's obviously a number of platforms where there's crypto-exchange,
or the platforms like yours are offering yield.
Do you believe yield on digital assets will be standard in the next couple, let's say, 12, 24 months?
Yeah, definitely. So it's just like the banking system, right?
So you had banks that opened up and they got structured products that come in and give yield to users.
We see that happen with crypto, right?
It starts with obviously the big larger assets like Bitcoin, Ethereum and other assets,
but we really see that actually becoming a really important topic for stablecoins, right?
As people hold stablecoins, how did they earn?
And we think that yield products are going to be the main ones to do it.
You know, on this, with the recent Genius Act in the US,
there's been a lot of pushback from the banks of not allowing crypto firms to offer yield,
because obviously they were from a competitive perspective.
What's your view on that?
You believe crypto exchanges will be the main firms, a big one.
That's the big exchanges that offer yield,
or the banks will need to adapt and try to offer at least competitive rates
to what you're getting using stablecoins.
Yeah, definitely see banks to adapt to this, right?
I mean, there's been a lot of conversation around banks offering their stablecoins,
like JPMorgan coming in.
So they are definitely going to be the biggest players,
but they still platforms like us, platforms like Coinbase and others,
they'll come in and they'll offer that.
So there's going to be a very competitive landscape going forward,
and I think it's quite exciting to see how people adapt to these changes.
What happens when yields go down?
Let's say there's a rate cut in the next couple of weeks or months.
How do you think that's going to impact yields on the obsolescence?
Yeah, it's a very good question.
We see that definitely the rates will go down.
That will impact stablecoins, right?
In the back they hold treasure bills.
T-bills around three to four percent, right?
There's going to be rate cuts coming in.
We see real-world assets to come in to these platforms
and being basically the source of yields as yields collapse, right?
So we're quite excited about that and us also are working towards
offering some real-world assets on the platform.
And how do you guys, what's your view on the customer protection angle, right?
When people go to banks, they really believe there's an FDIC coverage
or whatever they have in their each jurisdiction.
When it comes to such assets, especially post the events we've had two, three years ago,
where a lot of the yield offering firm is going down,
how do you believe the landscape has changed
when it comes to the firm's offering yield?
And I'm not talking about DeFi, but let's say on the more on the centralized side.
It's a very good question.
So the platforms we get more transparent, right, and decentralized.
So two, three years ago, all the platforms offered really high yields,
like 10, 15 percent yields, without telling users what's happening.
We think that's changed.
The other thing that crypto, especially like DeFi and also centralized platforms,
they're usually over collateralized, right?
You put a one collateral in, you're not going to get a one out,
you're going to get a 0.5 out, 0.7 out, which is pretty interesting.
It's not like the banking system, where you have under collateralized lending.
So we think this will how, basically, shape how people learn in the future
and we're quite excited about that.
And, you know, talking about the way Earn has generated, right?
We're seeing other rise of, let's say, what instruments or strategies
they used to be available before to institutional investors,
it's not being a very good example, now being accessible to retail.
Do you believe that digital assets will kind of democratize access to these strategies
that were previously available only to accredited professionals?
Definitely.
This is already happening, right?
You gave a good example, Athena.
This is a basis trade that was only available to hedge funds,
but now, obviously, users can come in.
There's a bit of understanding there, right?
So basically, you don't want to offer too risky products to retail,
but there's going to be more and more opportunities coming in.
Like, private credit, that was only available to institutions now,
Alton sitting in Dubai can essentially just, you know,
participate in those platforms.
So it's quite exciting.
And what about the user experience to always give the example of my lovely mom?
Maybe can go buy digital assets on a platform,
but whether she can use DeFi platforms for a yield or other yield generating platforms,
maybe not.
Where do you think the industry is now when it comes to the UX UI
to give access to people to yield solutions?
Yeah, it's improved.
Bridging and all the other ones, they were very complicated.
They're now abstracted.
Actually, the protocol I used to work at NIR really focused on this, right?
How do you do chain abstraction, which means you don't feel where the chain is.
You just want to come in and earn, like, the Revolut experience, right?
And that's where we're going, right?
That's where all the platforms, like, Revolut allows you to now buy cryptocurrency.
Eventually, I can see all of them offering, like, earn opportunities.
And it's already getting there, right?
The institutions are coming in.
They now want simplified experiences.
Our platform is one of the big, big, good examples.
You can log in with your Google account and, you know, you can just come in
and deposit a crypto and earn in, like, two, three clicks.
And that's what it's going to look like, right?
I think we're quite excited about that.
What do you think is going to be the new risk-free rate?
Obviously, now, with a lot of treasuries being tokenized,
do you believe we'll have treasure rate or whatever comes out afterwards?
Is the new risk-free rate or we'll have, like,
even staking of the various digital assets,
the staking yield becomes the risk-free rate that the industry use?
Or you think it'll be something different?
It's a good point.
So I think that's the benchmark.
So tokenized treasuries definitely will define how we earn in the crypto era.
But also staking, right?
If you're long on one of the assets that you hold in top 10, top 20,
that's coming from inflation.
It's quite similar to what, you know, U.S. does.
And we're quite excited about that.
There would be products offering, like, Athena did, for example.
You can come with ETH, you earn the staking yield and you earn a bit more.
But obviously, that depends on the risk profiles of the users.
What's your view from, let's say, the regulator perspective, right?
So as we see more and more regulators look at the space,
do you believe regulators will need to embrace this different yield offering platforms
and even offerings that we're seeing across from exchanges?
Or do you believe there'll be more of a clamp down over the next couple of years,
especially following the lobby from a lot of the big banks
who will see a lot of their revenues go out, potentially, especially with younger users?
Yeah, they definitely have to embrace, right?
I mean, Genius is a good example, right?
If you hold stablecoins, it doesn't allow you to offer yield, which makes sense, right?
You know that if you offer stablecoins as a bare bone,
you're not exposed to any risk except to T-bills, except some smart contract risk.
But going forward, I think every sort of step that you add,
you need to tell the user this is what's happening.
And this is what we do, right?
With transparent reports that we release, we tell the users,
"Hey, the yield is coming from Ethereum.
This is the market that we're using."
I think that's going to be the platform and that's going to be the kind of the way forward.
What's the biggest risk you see?
Let's see, looking down the horizon of the crypto ecosystem,
especially when it comes to yield offering platforms for the next five years.
What is the one risk that you have at the back of your mind
that you think can actually come and cause damage to the ecosystem?
It is the same risks, right?
It's basically yield being centralized in two, three different players
and if something happens to the one player, even though it's over-collateralized,
you still run into the risk of a one organization.
This is why we start a crypto.
Crypto needs to be a bit more decentralized, more players, less risk among the people.
And so that's why we're quite excited about the offerings of DeFi.
For example, offering that to users.
Yeah, so that's the main risk I see.
And quickly in 30 seconds, Alta.
Between the yield generating on CFI and DeFi platforms,
how do you see that happening?
Do you believe they'll just yield regenerated users who don't know
how it's been generated behind the scenes?
Or do you see these two ecosystem quabbatating or actually users
choosing one over the other the next couple of years?
Yeah, it is going to be like the banking system, right?
So there's structure products, you go to UBS, they sell you structure products.
I see it quite the same way, right?
Like you have a one platform that come in, it could be CFI, DeFi,
low-risk, medium-risk, high-risk, obviously tell the user what the risks are.
But I really see those being collapsed, right?
I mean, a good example I gave you earlier, Coinbase is working with Steakhouse.
Steakhouse is a DeFi provider, Coinbase is a centralized exchange.
So they're coming together to offer yield opportunities on DeFi to the CFI users,
and that's the biggest shift.
A lot of exciting things happening in that space.
That was Alta and Tutarh, the CEO co-founder of More Markets.
Very exciting developments going on in the broader yield space.
Thank you Alta and for being with us today.